João Dias designer & developer



I make stuff for the web.

I'm João — an interface designer and frontend developer based in Coimbra, Portugal.

I've been working in this industry for over 9 years and now mostly specialized in UX Design and Web Development for all kinds of screen sizes and users.

WIT Software is where I work since 2013 but I also enjoy my side projects. and I'm always looking forward to new and interesting professional challenges!

Experience

UI Designer and Web Developer 2013 - Today

UI Designer 2011 - 2013

Web Designer 2011 - 2013 WIT SOFTWARE

Main focus on interface design as well as frontend web development.

LOAD INTERACTIVE

The do-it-all-designer at a mobile development startup.

JOAODIAS.ME

Early years as a freelance web designer.

Skillset

VISUAL TOOLS

Sketch, Figma, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator and Indesign. Principle, Facebook Origami and Keynote.

DEVELOPMENT

HTML, CSS, React, Redux, Vue, Vuex, Gatsby, Next, jQuery, Wordpress, Git.

OTHERS

User Research, Usability, Acessibility, Video and Audio production.

Education

ESEC, Portugal Class of 2011

ESEC, Portugal 2007 - 2008

Bernardino Machado School Class of 2007 Degree in Communication and Multimedia Design

1st year in Organizational Communication

High School in Computers and Informatics

Skillset

Besides taking the time to learn new skills every week, I also enjoy spending family time -- specially with my son -- as well as the usual workout and rocking out to some good rock, metal and otther types of good music.